Lisa, stop!
How can you possibly expect to beat us when you have no powers to speak of?
You don't have to do this, Lisa!
Due to the plague that is human combustion, weak men like you live and die at the mercy of the flames.
But through Lisa's compatibility with the bugs, she's kindled the flames within herself.
Both of my parents were killed during a fire that was caused by an infernal.
After that, I lived in terror until the bug awakened my power and drove my fear away.
These guys are lying to you, Lisa!
I don't have any more powers than you did as a kid.
And as a fire soldier, I know the terror of the flames as well as anyone.
I face it every day!
Seems to me that Giovanni wants you to be scared.
He's using your fear to control you!
You accuse me as you brandish an axe at her.
The axe is for you!
He doesn't care about you, Lisa!
You have no reason to protect him!
The flaming tentacles which envelop me are magnetically attuned, so they move to protect me of their own accord.
The flames I used to live in fear of now keep me safe!
What kind of bug is able to give people powers like that?
Would you like to know?
Well, I'm not killing!
You'll leave this world just as ignorant as you were coming in!
You are one annoying old man!
Did you actually believe that you could put out my fire with a toy like that?
I don't think it's gonna work, Captain!
We'll see about that!
It seems like this fight is a joke to you.
It's not, I promise.
I'm trying my hardest to save you from the flames that hold you captive.
So hang in there!
I am not their captive!
If those feelers aren't defending you, why do you look so scared?
I'm not scared, but you should be!
I'm not fighting you!
I'm fighting a fire!
Fire extinguishers have no place on the field of battle.
You truly are a fool.
You've forgotten, but there's a motto we fire soldiers live by.
Protect human life and property.
This piece of gear might not be flashy, but it does its job every time.
It saved more lives than I can count!
Kill them.
Yes, right.
Your naivety will be the death of you.
Tell me, how do you plan to keep saving people's lives when you've thrown your own away?
Believe it or not, I'm very protective of my life.
I'm sorry for making you wait, Lisa.
But everything's in place now.
Obi!
You took all those hits on purpose, so you could place extinguisher grenades beneath her tentacles!
I'm falling.
I've lost everything.
Everyone.
Mom.
Dad.
Fuck it.
You haven't forgotten what you are again, have you, feeler?
Take what you got and leave now, you're wearing out your welcome No one here wants to see you here, yeah Think that you won from day one, once the devil will come You know just why he wants you, don't you?
Your crooked desire, it doesn't seem so right Miscuited, divided, at the point of the reason You're starting a fire, you gotta watch it burn Try to save yourself like you always do
Every bridge we've built, you think it's just a burning death Just burn it down, when everything is gone
You wish you only heard us out, heard us out Screaming, Miscuited, Miscuited
Miscuited, Miscuited
It was I who saved you from the fear of the flames I who gave you purpose Vulcan never would have given you a home if not for me You'd best remember the debt you owe Come back here
Don't do this I have to, though Back when I had absolutely nothing, Dr. Giovanni came and rescued me I can't leave him now
Just try to forget we ever met, okay?
Damn you!
Take one more step and I'll burn through her neck with this wire
Listen well, Vulcan If you want to save her life, you'll do exactly as I say
Pick up that gun and shoot Obi
You really are a rotten bastard to the core
You should rejoice, Fela Your life is being put to use in the service of the Evangelist right now
Isn't that what you want?
Vulcan, do as he says
Huh?
Sorry, sir
This isn't your fault
No more stalling
Act now or else
There's no point in making a big production out of it
Just do as I say
Shoot and Fela will live
Don't and Lisa will die
That's all there is to it.
I swear I'm gonna kill you, Giovanni!
Are you?
Well, before you do, you can watch as my heating wire lops off this poor girl's head.
Go ahead. Pull the trigger.
It's the only way you can save Lisa.
I can't do it.
Then Lisa is finished.
Do it, Vulcan! Shoot me!
If you don't, he'll kill Lisa.
But if I give in, then...
You killed your captain and your only chance of winning just to save this girl.
Lisa.
Captain.
Ha ha ha ha ha...
Huh?
Even knowing I'd be fine, that was scary!
Giovanni!
That turnout coat isn't made to be bulletproof.
So what extra protection did you have?
Oh. Would you like to know?
Huh?
You feeling curious?
Well, I'm not gonna tell you!
I gave him a special holistic vest before we came!
Hmm...
I'm working as the 8th Engineer now!
There's no way I'm gonna let my captain fight without protection!
Even so, that was a reckless ploy.
It's the trust we put into each other that makes the members of Company 8 a real team.
Trust? What an absurd, inexplicable concept!
Your hardware's a disorganized mess!
You're lucky that Pop isn't here to see it!
Get ready, dirtbag! Equip penguin mess!
Let's see if that machinery of yours can pass a strike test!
Your hardware's as weak as it looks!
Lisa!
Good work, I'll take over!
Considering your lack of powers, you're managing quite well.
You used to be a fire soldier like me.
You were meant to protect people from the flames.
Why would you go from saving people to turning them into infernals?
What does your evangelist hope to accomplish by spreading so much terror?
Earlier you told me that the fire soldier's maxim was to protect human life and property.
Did you not?
Tell me, can you really not see how trivial such things are?
Humans are such a small portion of the Earth's energy.
We are vermin scuttling across the planet's crust.
Of course, mankind should burn.
It's the only way to become part of something greater!
I'm on a clap!
About 250 years ago, this planet's surface was torn apart by the great king.
You're still trying to be the greatest universe of million attentions of all the
minds of humans, and we must really not see how trivial such things are.
Humans are such a small portion of the Earth's energy.
We are vermin scuttling across the planet's crust.
Of course, mankind should burn.
It's the only way to become part of something greater!
I'm on a clap!
About 250 years ago, this planet's surface was torn apart by the great cataclysm.
This catastrophe was caused by the sudden release of an immense Adola Burst, and the place that Adola Burst came from is one you know.
It's a place you believe in, if you have faith.
Long before the solar calendar began, before the Great Cataclysm, since time immemorial, humankind has lived in perpetual fear of this place.
Regardless of what causes spontaneous human combustion, I'll do my damndest to stop it. You still haven't made a case for burning people alive.
Spontaneous human combustion is a part of the natural order. Would you defy the laws of nature?
The bugs you use are made by people!
Do you earnestly believe that the Evangelist is no more than a regular person?
It doesn't matter what the Evangelist really is. Your cult wanted an idol to worship, so you prop one up for yourselves.
Honestly, what a ridiculous notion. You say that we worship an idol, then what's the great sun god of the Holy Soul Temple?
Why bother offering prayers that you don't know will be answered to a god that you don't know exists?
Yeah? Well, at least the temple doesn't go around roasting people.
The Evangelist is no mere idol.
A powerless man such as yourself cannot comprehend what the Evangelist is.
But that truth is likely beginning to dawn on your soldier, Shinra Kusakabe.
You good, Shinra? Talk to me.
Where am I?
What is this?
Who...
Who are you?
Shinra?
Show?
Shira?
You okay?
What happened?
I...
I don't know.
What's the matter?
Do you see something?
It's Sho.
He's up ahead, waiting.
As we speak, Shinra Kusakabe's Adola Burst will be getting stronger through his link with
Commander Sho.
Link?
How exactly are they connected?
What is an Adola Burst, really?
It is a special flame, belonging to those who have become more than pyrokinetics.
It affects all forms of heat, and it's the spark from which infernals spring.
You're saying that an Adola Burst like Shinra's are what make infernals?
Then what are those bugs you people use?
You wish to know how they relate.
Insects took a drastically different evolutionary path than the rest of the animal kingdom.
Which begs the question, where do bugs come from?
Some say it's the same place as the Adola Burst.
Like moths to a flame.
Perhaps every burnt insect is a child who tried to find its mother.
So you came after all, Shinra Kusakabe?
Yeah.
I came here to keep my promise.
You say you made a vow, Knave.
To whom?
To Mom.
The woman who loved us both.
I have but one mother figure in my life, and that is the Evangelist.
The thought that you're my brother turns my stomach.
How can that be?
I was not born from some filthy womb.
Don't talk about Mom like that.
I'm about to watch two Adola Bursts go flame to flame.
This is awesome!
The end, please!
Oh, my God.
Here I was hoping we could catch up a bit.
You saw that, too.
That wasn't just fast.
It was like he stopped time.
How can a pyrokinetic do that?
Hey, Captain!
Lieutenant Hinoa!
Maki!
Found you!
This lesson is over.
My task was to get Shinra Kusukabe to Commander Shou.
Now that this objective has been accomplished,
I have no need to stall for any more time.
All is in accordance with the will of the Evangelist.
Hold it!
So Adola Bursts are the cause of human combustion, huh?
What the hell is happening to the world right now?
Yeah, just keep walking!
I'll leave Lisa with you.
But you will never reverse her conditioning.
Please don't leave me behind.
I'll do anything you told me to.
I'll be good.
Lisa!
Faith.
Religion.
Brainwashing.
The ailments mankind could never cure.
Farewell.
It doesn't matter how swiftly you can move.
You will never be able to match me, Knave.
The fact is that you and I exist in two separate universes.
Universes?
Hold on.
What are you saying?
That you're on a different level than me?
So you think I should just give up?
I'm taking you home if I had to drag you kicking and screaming!
You play tag kind of rough, little bro.
The universe has time freezing.
If he's engaging enough heat to expand the whole universe...
No.
That can't be.
Even if he is a third generation,
is that kind of thing really possible?
Xenra, we need to run!
I'm serious, you don't stand a chance here!
His power's too much!
Huh?
Then have you figured out how his power works?
You can move as fast as you want in your universe.
That's meaningless to me.
Because in my universe, I am fully in command.
You're in command of your own universe.
The hell's that supposed to mean?
Is this another Adola Link?
This is something that's better shown than explained with mere words.
All right, we got metaphors.
Firstly, what does it mean?
I'll see you next time.